

Abduljaleel Sajid

Resort Manager / Revenue Manager / Reservations Manager

MBA - Hospitality Management | BA - Psychology | Bachelor of Commerce | DCA

+91 871 401 313 7



abduljaleel.sajid@gmail.com



Kerala, India



ww.linkedin.com/abduljaleel-sajid



EDUCATION

M.B.A Management Hospitality

B.A - Psychology

Bachelor

of

Commerce

Diploma in Computer Applications

Achievements:

Highest RGI Growth - 2016 Symphony Style Hotel, Kuwait.

System Delivery Uplifting (19% – 36%) – InterContinental Al Khobar – K.S.A.

Highest Re-conversion Ratio -InterContinental Al Khobar -K.S.A

SKILLS

10 / 10

Attention to Detail / Creative Thinking

10 / 10

PMS - Opera 5.0, Fidelio 6.20

10 / 10

RMS – Revenue Management Systems

9.5 / 10

Leadership & Organizational Skills

9.5 / 10

MS Office Applications

ABOUT ME

esults driven committed leader with over 20 years of experience in the Hospitality Industry across Middle East & India Markets.

Having a strong technical & business acumen with proven and acknowledged leadership competencies and selfmotivated with a drive to deliver results with clearly defined objectives. Vastly exposed to multi-cultural work environments, with 5 Pre-Opening experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Revenue Manager

Holiday Inn Agra / India / Jul 2021 - Present

Develop and implement strategies to ensure revenue and room night sales goals are achieved, Revenue strategies are set, tactical plans are created and implemented, and results are monitored and achieved.

//////// Covid-19 Redundant \\\\\\\\

Resort Manager (Pre-opening Project)

State Beach Resort / Kannur, Kerala - India / Jan 2020 - Sep 2020

Responsible for maintaining the overall operation of the Resort, delivering high quality leadership behaviors and engaging every team member to play a vital role in continuously improving the service. I also drive operational excellence in the resort by maximizing financial returns, guiding the continuous development of our people, creating and maintaining an exceptional guest experience through consistent, gracious and anticipatory service, executing on brand standards, and building awareness of the uniqueness of our resort and the brand in the local community.

Cluster Revenue Manager (Pre-Opening Project)

Somewhere Hotels Group / U.A.E & K.S.A / May 2018 - Jan 2020

As a Cluster Revenue Manager, I am managing revenue for up to three properties across the company's portfolio. I am also responsible to maximize revenue, market share and profits for multiple hotels through the strategic coordination of revenue management processes and procedures.

Revenue & Reservations Manager

Symphony Style Hotel - Carlson Rezidor Hotels Group / Kuwait / Jul 2015 - Jan 2018

Manage and maintain group and transient inventory controls. Develop, monitor, and adjust sales and pricing strategies. Provide critical analysis of strategies, room's statistics and demand factors. Conduct analyses of prices offered by other hotels to develop competitive prices and discounts.

Abduljaleel Sajid

"Your USP is never what you think it is, it is what your customer think it is"

INTERESTS



Travel



Reading



Volunteering / Public Service



Cooking

PERSONAL

Date of Birth

28th Nov 1979

Place of Birth

Kerala

Gender

Male

Marital Status

Married

Nationality

Indian

Linguistic Proficiency

English, Arabic, Malayalam, Tamil, Urdu & Hindi

Personal Strengths:

Very Adaptable.
Openness (Sharing Ideas).
Time Management Ability.
Leadership Qualities.
Prompt in Decision Making.
Excellent Communication Skills.
Good Inter-Personal Strengths.
Conscientious.
Intent approach to vary situations.

Revenue & Reservations Manager (Pre-Opening Project)

Banana Island Resort by Anantara / Doha - Qatar / Oct 2014 - Apr 2015

Manage and maintain group and transient inventory controls. Develop, monitor, and adjust sales and pricing strategies. Provide critical analysis of strategies, room's statistics and demand factors. Conduct analyses of prices offered by other hotels to develop competitive prices and discounts.

Reservations Manager

Divan Erbil - Preferred Hotels Group / Erbil - Irag / Jun 2013 - Jun 2014

Ensures the smooth & efficient operations in the Reservations Department through prompt, effective and proper service to achieve maximum room revenue in order to meet / exceed the revenue targets. Supervising and coaching the reservations staff & implementing P&P under the Brand guidance.

Reservations Manager (Pre-Opening Project)

Crowne Plaza Madinah / Madinah - Saudi Arabia / Jun 2012 - May 2013

Responsible for driving profitability by selling the right product, to the right customer, at the right price through the right sales channel within every area of the hotel.

Reservations Manager (Pre-Opening Project)

InterContinental Al Khobar / Al Khobar - Saudi Arabia / Nov 2007 - Jun 2012

Responsible for driving profitability by selling the right product, to the right customer, at the right price through the right sales channel within every area of the hotel. Joined as the Asst. Reservations Manager & got promoted as Reservations Manager within a year.

Various Positions (Front Office, Sales & Reservations)

InterContinental Jeddah / Jeddah - Saudi Arabia / Jan 2001 - Apr 2007

Career oriented in-depth exposure within different departments at IC Jeddah, which includes Front Office Operations, Sales & Marketing and Reservations Department.

Certifications

Rooms Revenue Academy.

Maximizing Channels / Channel Management Workshop.

Solution Selling / Strategic Selling Process.

Opera OXI Management.

Profitable Revenue Management Workshop.

Managing Training & Development for Business.

How to run an effective Revenue Meeting.

Reservation Selling Techniques.

Guest Courtesy Trainings.

Leading Effective Meetings.

Hotel Content Manager.

